<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
<properties>
    <title>Enterprise Job Scheduler for .NET Platform</title>
</properties>
	<body>
		<intro>
		</intro>

		<section id="welcome">
			<title>Welcome to the home of Quartz.NET!</title>
			<p>
				<br />
				<cite>Quartz.NET is a full-featured, open source job scheduling system that can be used from smallest apps to large scale enterprise systems.</cite>
			</p>
			<p>
				Quartz.NET is a port of very propular open source Java job scheduling framework, <a href="http://www.opensymphony.com/quartz">Quartz</a>. 
				This project owes very much to original Java project, it's father James House and
				the project contributors. 
			</p>
			<p>
				Quartz.NET is a pure .NET library written in C# which currently targets Framework version 1.1 and above.
				Quartz.NET is feature-wise equal to Quartz Java 1.6 excluding Java specifics. Quartz.NET
				is already running in production systems and has received good feedback.
			</p>
		</section>

		<section id="news">
			<title>News</title>

			<section>
				<title>Quartz.NET 1.0 RC 2 Released</title>
				<p>
				<div class="descr">August 6, 2008 by Marko Lahma</div>
				</p>
				<p>
					Quartz.NET 1.0 RC 2 has been released. This release is the 
					second release candidate for final 1.0 release. 
				</p>

				<p>
					This release contains late minute breaking change. All time
					interval and duration related data that was presented with
					longs or ints before is now presented with TimeSpans which
					is a more natural way for .NET. This change will cause
					compile time errors that should be quite easy to fix using
					TimeSpan.FromXXX methods. Where you earlier had 5000 milliseconds
					you can now use a more convenient form of TimeSpan.FromSeconds(5).
				</p>
				<p>
					Please refer to the
					<a href="http://jira.opensymphony.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=10110&amp;styleName=Html&amp;version=21784">release notes</a> 
					and the readme.txt in the release bundle for more information.
				</p>
				<p>
					Grab it from <a href="download.html">downloads page</a>.
				</p>
			</section>
			
			<section>
				<title>Quartz.NET 1.0 RC 1 Released</title>
				<p>
				<div class="descr">July 28, 2008 by Marko Lahma</div>
				</p>
				<p>
					Quartz.NET 1.0 RC 1 has been released. This release is the 
					first release candidate for final 1.0 release. In this release
					you can find some minor bug fixes, small improvements and 
					the new Quartz.NET simple server for running jobs. 
					
					Please refer to the
					<a href="http://jira.opensymphony.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=10110&amp;styleName=Html&amp;version=21750">release notes</a> 
					and the readme.txt in the release bundle for more information.
				</p>
				<p>
					Grab it from <a href="download.html">downloads page</a>.
				</p>
			</section>
			
			<section>
				<title>Quartz.NET 0.9.1 Released</title>
				<p>
				<div class="descr">January 20, 2008 by Marko Lahma</div>
				</p>
				<p>
					Quartz.NET 0.9.1 has been released. This a bug fix version
					which fixes problems and inconveniences found in earlier
					0.9 release. Please refer to the
					<a href="http://jira.opensymphony.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=10110&amp;styleName=Html&amp;version=21760">release notes</a> 
					for more information.
				</p>
				<p>
					Grab it from <a href="download.html">downloads page</a>.
				</p>
			</section>


			<section>
				<title>Quartz.NET 0.9 Released</title>
				<p>
				<div class="descr">December 1, 2007 by Marko Lahma</div>
				</p>
				<p>
					Quartz.NET 0.9 has been released. This is the earlier 0.7
					version renamed to indicate maturity and feature completeness.
				</p>
				<p>
					This is again a feature release also containing
					some minor bug fixes. The biggest new features are support for XML
					based configuration for setting up the scheduler and remoting 
					exporting support for the scheduler.
					XML configuration should make it now easier
					to define your scheduling out-of-code regardless of the used job store.
					Remoting functionality allows you to control scheduler over 
					application domain boundaries.
				</p>
				<p>
					The Quartz.NET DLL is now also finally signed assembly and
					you can add it to the GAC.
				</p>
				<p>
					<strong>
						This release has also major breaking change: all times
						are now expected to be in UTC time zone for Quartz.NET to work
						correctly.
					</strong>
					<br />
					Please check <a href="migration_guide.html">migration guide</a>
					before upgrading.
				</p>
				<p>
					Please refer to examples to see XML configuration and remoting
					in action. The documentation is still work in progress.
				</p>
				<p>
					<strong>
						UPDATE: XML configuration example's XML file isn't valid
						according to its schema. The "allows-transient-data"
						attribute hsa been removed from the Quartz.NET XML schema
						and can be safely removed from the XML file aswell.
					</strong>
				</p>
				<p>
					Grab it from <a href="download.html">downloads page</a>.
				</p>
			</section>

			<section>
				<title>Project News</title>
				<p>
				<div class="descr">August 8, 2007 by Marko Lahma</div>
				</p>
				<p>
					Now that version 0.6 was released with quite impressive feature set
					it's a good time to sit back and elaborate a bit what's been up with the project.
				</p>
				<p>
					Project has received free license for Clover.NET from kind folks at <a href="http://www.cenqua.com/">Cenqua</a>
					(actually now Atlassian - the're cool people too!),
					and did we receive it right on time - product will be discontinued and I believe no 
					further licenses will be given. Cenqua also has opened a 
					<a href="http://fisheye3.cenqua.com/browse/quartznet">FishEye view of the source code</a>.
				</p>
				<p>
					The folks at <a href="http://www.innovasys.com">Innovasys</a> also support open source and they gave us a free license
					for their excellent source code documentation management software <a href="http://www.innovasys.com/products/documentx.asp">Document! X</a>
				</p>
				<p>
					So what's going to happen next? We've caught up with Java version 1.6 already quite nicely but there are still a couple of big things to do:
				</p>
				<ul>
					<li>XML based configuration support - ability to define jobs and triggers in XML configuration file</li>
					<li>Spring.NET support - actually I've already got running code that seems to work but there are still some issues to solve</li>
				</ul>
				<p>
					After XML configuration is working and released (planned for 0.7) it's getting close to 1.0 time. Even though
					Quartz.NET is quite production ready as-is, it'll be considered 1.0 when it's also feature ready.
				</p>
				<p>
					Please remember, It's your feedback that drives this project! So don't hesitate to bring up the the good and the bad
					in Quartz.NET. We gladly accept bug reports (better yet with test code to illustrate and maybe even a patch to fix it!)
					to our <a href="http://jira.opensymphony.com/browse/QRTZNET">JIRA issue tracker</a> and welcome questions and help 
					requests to <a href="http://groups.google.com/group/quartznet">Quartz.NET mailing list</a>. It would also be great
					to hear about projects/products using Quartz.NET!
				</p>
			</section>


			<section>
				<title></title>
				<p>
					Older news can be found from the <a href="old_news.html">news archive >></a>.
				</p>
			</section>
		</section>
	</body>
</document>