<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
<properties>
    <title>Enterprise Job Scheduler for .NET Platform</title>
</properties>
	<body>
		<intro>
		</intro>

		<section id="welcome">
			<title>Welcome to the home of Quartz.NET!</title>
			<p>
				<br />
				<cite>Quartz.NET is a full-featured, open source job scheduling system that can be used from smallest apps to large scale enterprise systems.</cite>
			</p>
			<p>
				Quartz.NET is a port of very propular open source Java job scheduling framework, <a href="http://www.opensymphony.com/quartz">Quartz</a>. 
				This project owes very much to original Java project, it's father James House and
				the project contributors. 
			</p>
			<p>
				Quartz.NET is a pure .NET library written in C# which currently targets Framework version 1.1 and above.
				Quartz.NET is feature-wise equal to Quartz Java 1.6 excluding Java specifics. Quartz.NET
				is already running in production systems and has received good feedback.
			</p>
		</section>

		<section id="news">
			<title>News</title>
			
			<section>
				<title>Quartz.NET 1.0.2 Released</title>
				<p>
				<div class="descr">December 12, 2009 by Marko Lahma</div>
				</p>
				<p>
					Quartz.NET 1.0.2 has been released.
				</p>
				<p>
					This is a maintenance release for the 1.0 development branch of Quartz.NET an probably also the last release supporting .NET Framework 1.1.
					Further development efforts will go to Quartz.NET 1.2 that no longer supports 1.1 Framework.
				</p>
				<p>
					This version corresponds to Java Quartz's version 1.6.6.
				</p>
				<p>
					Please refer to the
					<a href="http://jira.opensymphony.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=10110&amp;styleName=Html&amp;version=21825">release notes</a> 
					and the readme.txt in the release bundle for more information.
				</p>
				<p>
					Grab it from <a href="download.html">downloads page</a>.
				</p>
			</section>	
			
			<section>
				<title>Quartz.NET 1.0.1 Released</title>
				<p>
				<div class="descr">May 16, 2009 by Marko Lahma</div>
				</p>
				<p>
					Quartz.NET 1.0.1 has been released and it's an advised update for everyone.
				</p>
				<p>
					This release includes bug fixes to issues found in 1.0 release
					and also includes performance optimization to AdoJobStore 
					when Quartz.NET is handling a lot of triggers. Quarz.NET no 
					longer loads all of them but is able limit the query results
					by using a custom SQL delegate. Quartz.NET issues a warning
					on startup if custom delegate is not used. Available delegates
					include ones for SQL Server, Oracle, SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL
					and Firebird.
				</p>
				<p>
					Please refer to the
					<a href="http://jira.opensymphony.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=10110&amp;styleName=Html&amp;version=21794">release notes</a> 
					and the readme.txt in the release bundle for more information.
				</p>
				<p>
					Grab it from <a href="download.html">downloads page</a>.
				</p>
			</section>	

			<section>
				<title>Quartz.NET 1.0 Final Released</title>
				<p>
				<div class="descr">November 6, 2008 by Marko Lahma</div>
				</p>
				<p>
					I'm happy to announce that Quartz.NET 1.0 Final has been released.
					This release marks a big milestone for Quartz.NET development.
					After more than two years of development, bug fixing and new features
					Quartz.NET has finally matured to version 1.0. This version
					corresponds to Java Quartz version 1.6.2.
				</p>

				<p>
					I would like to thank everyone involved with Quartz.NET, whether
					you have been just a happy user, bug reporter or a patch supplier, 
					your help has been more than appreciated and helped along the way.
					Special thanks to James House and his team for their continuous
					effort to make Quartz better.
				</p>
				<p>
					Please refer to the
					<a href="http://jira.opensymphony.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=10110&amp;styleName=Html&amp;version=21783">release notes</a> 
					and the readme.txt in the release bundle for more information.
				</p>
				<p>
					Grab it from <a href="download.html">downloads page</a>.
				</p>
			</section>	
			

			
			<section>
				<title></title>
				<p>
					Older news can be found from the <a href="old_news.html">news archive >></a>.
				</p>
			</section>
		</section>
	</body>
</document>