<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
	<properties>
	    <title>News archive</title>
	</properties>
	<body>
		<intro>
		</intro>
	
		<section>
			<title>News archive</title>

			<section>
				<title>Quartz.NET 1.0.2 Released</title>
				<p>
				<div class="descr">December 12, 2009 by Marko Lahma</div>
				</p>
				<p>
					Quartz.NET 1.0.2 has been released.
				</p>
				<p>
					This is a maintenance release for the 1.0 development branch of Quartz.NET an probably also the last release supporting .NET Framework 1.1.
					Further development efforts will go to Quartz.NET 1.2 that no longer supports 1.1 Framework.
				</p>
				<p>
					This version corresponds to Java Quartz's version 1.6.6.
				</p>
				<p>
					Please refer to the
					<a href="http://jira.opensymphony.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=10110&amp;styleName=Html&amp;version=21825">release notes</a> 
					and the readme.txt in the release bundle for more information.
				</p>
				<p>
					Grab it from <a href="download.html">downloads page</a>.
				</p>
			</section>	
			
			<section>
				<title>Quartz.NET 1.0.1 Released</title>
				<p>
				<div class="descr">May 16, 2009 by Marko Lahma</div>
				</p>
				<p>
					Quartz.NET 1.0.1 has been released and it's an advised update for everyone.
				</p>
				<p>
					This release includes bug fixes to issues found in 1.0 release
					and also includes performance optimization to AdoJobStore 
					when Quartz.NET is handling a lot of triggers. Quarz.NET no 
					longer loads all of them but is able limit the query results
					by using a custom SQL delegate. Quartz.NET issues a warning
					on startup if custom delegate is not used. Available delegates
					include ones for SQL Server, Oracle, SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL
					and Firebird.
				</p>
				<p>
					Please refer to the
					<a href="http://jira.opensymphony.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=10110&amp;styleName=Html&amp;version=21794">release notes</a> 
					and the readme.txt in the release bundle for more information.
				</p>
				<p>
					Grab it from <a href="download.html">downloads page</a>.
				</p>
			</section>	

			<section>
				<title>Quartz.NET 1.0 Final Released</title>
				<p>
				<div class="descr">November 6, 2008 by Marko Lahma</div>
				</p>
				<p>
					I'm happy to announce that Quartz.NET 1.0 Final has been released.
					This release marks a big milestone for Quartz.NET development.
					After more than two years of development, bug fixing and new features
					Quartz.NET has finally matured to version 1.0. This version
					corresponds to Java Quartz version 1.6.2.
				</p>

				<p>
					I would like to thank everyone involved with Quartz.NET, whether
					you have been just a happy user, bug reporter or a patch supplier, 
					your help has been more than appreciated and helped along the way.
					Special thanks to James House and his team for their continuous
					effort to make Quartz better.
				</p>
				<p>
					Please refer to the
					<a href="http://jira.opensymphony.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=10110&amp;styleName=Html&amp;version=21783">release notes</a> 
					and the readme.txt in the release bundle for more information.
				</p>
				<p>
					Grab it from <a href="download.html">downloads page</a>.
				</p>
			</section>	
			
			<section>
				<title>Quartz.NET 1.0 RC 3 Released</title>
				<p>
				<div class="descr">September 6, 2008 by Marko Lahma</div>
				</p>
				<p>
					Quartz.NET 1.0 RC 3 has been released. This release is the 
					third release candidate for final 1.0 release. 
				</p>

				<p>
					This release is a bug fix release and also adds the Quartz.NET
					server source to standard distribution. Everyone using earlier
					release candidate is adviced to upgrade.
				</p>
				<p>
					Please refer to the
					<a href="http://jira.opensymphony.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=10110&amp;styleName=Html&amp;version=21785">release notes</a> 
					and the readme.txt in the release bundle for more information.
				</p>
				<p>
					Grab it from <a href="download.html">downloads page</a>.
				</p>
			</section>			
			
			<section>
				<title>Quartz.NET 1.0 RC 2 Released</title>
				<p>
				<div class="descr">August 6, 2008 by Marko Lahma</div>
				</p>
				<p>
					Quartz.NET 1.0 RC 2 has been released. This release is the 
					second release candidate for final 1.0 release. 
				</p>

				<p>
					This release contains late minute breaking change. All time
					interval and duration related data that was presented with
					longs or ints before is now presented with TimeSpans which
					is a more natural way for .NET. This change will cause
					compile time errors that should be quite easy to fix using
					TimeSpan.FromXXX methods. Where you earlier had 5000 milliseconds
					you can now use a more convenient form of TimeSpan.FromSeconds(5).
				</p>
				<p>
					Please refer to the
					<a href="http://jira.opensymphony.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=10110&amp;styleName=Html&amp;version=21784">release notes</a> 
					and the readme.txt in the release bundle for more information.
				</p>
				<p>
					Grab it from <a href="download.html">downloads page</a>.
				</p>
			</section>
			
			<section>
				<title>Quartz.NET 1.0 RC 1 Released</title>
				<p>
				<div class="descr">July 28, 2008 by Marko Lahma</div>
				</p>
				<p>
					Quartz.NET 1.0 RC 1 has been released. This release is the 
					first release candidate for final 1.0 release. In this release
					you can find some minor bug fixes, small improvements and 
					the new Quartz.NET simple server for running jobs. 
					
					Please refer to the
					<a href="http://jira.opensymphony.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=10110&amp;styleName=Html&amp;version=21750">release notes</a> 
					and the readme.txt in the release bundle for more information.
				</p>
				<p>
					Grab it from <a href="download.html">downloads page</a>.
				</p>
			</section>
			
			<section>
				<title>Quartz.NET 0.9.1 Released</title>
				<p>
				<div class="descr">January 20, 2008 by Marko Lahma</div>
				</p>
				<p>
					Quartz.NET 0.9.1 has been released. This a bug fix version
					which fixes problems and inconveniences found in earlier
					0.9 release. Please refer to the
					<a href="http://jira.opensymphony.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=10110&amp;styleName=Html&amp;version=21760">release notes</a> 
					for more information.
				</p>
				<p>
					Grab it from <a href="download.html">downloads page</a>.
				</p>
			</section>


			<section>
				<title>Quartz.NET 0.9 Released</title>
				<p>
				<div class="descr">December 1, 2007 by Marko Lahma</div>
				</p>
				<p>
					Quartz.NET 0.9 has been released. This is the earlier 0.7
					version renamed to indicate maturity and feature completeness.
				</p>
				<p>
					This is again a feature release also containing
					some minor bug fixes. The biggest new features are support for XML
					based configuration for setting up the scheduler and remoting 
					exporting support for the scheduler.
					XML configuration should make it now easier
					to define your scheduling out-of-code regardless of the used job store.
					Remoting functionality allows you to control scheduler over 
					application domain boundaries.
				</p>
				<p>
					The Quartz.NET DLL is now also finally signed assembly and
					you can add it to the GAC.
				</p>
				<p>
					<strong>
						This release has also major breaking change: all times
						are now expected to be in UTC time zone for Quartz.NET to work
						correctly.
					</strong>
					<br />
					Please check <a href="migration_guide.html">migration guide</a>
					before upgrading.
				</p>
				<p>
					Please refer to examples to see XML configuration and remoting
					in action. The documentation is still work in progress.
				</p>
				<p>
					<strong>
						UPDATE: XML configuration example's XML file isn't valid
						according to its schema. The "allows-transient-data"
						attribute hsa been removed from the Quartz.NET XML schema
						and can be safely removed from the XML file aswell.
					</strong>
				</p>
				<p>
					Grab it from <a href="download.html">downloads page</a>.
				</p>
			</section>

			<section>
				<title>Project News</title>
				<p>
				<div class="descr">August 8, 2007 by Marko Lahma</div>
				</p>
				<p>
					Now that version 0.6 was released with quite impressive feature set
					it's a good time to sit back and elaborate a bit what's been up with the project.
				</p>
				<p>
					Project has received free license for Clover.NET from kind folks at <a href="http://www.cenqua.com/">Cenqua</a>
					(actually now Atlassian - the're cool people too!),
					and did we receive it right on time - product will be discontinued and I believe no 
					further licenses will be given. Cenqua also has opened a 
					<a href="http://fisheye3.cenqua.com/browse/quartznet">FishEye view of the source code</a>.
				</p>
				<p>
					The folks at <a href="http://www.innovasys.com">Innovasys</a> also support open source and they gave us a free license
					for their excellent source code documentation management software <a href="http://www.innovasys.com/products/documentx.asp">Document! X</a>
				</p>
				<p>
					So what's going to happen next? We've caught up with Java version 1.6 already quite nicely but there are still a couple of big things to do:
				</p>
				<ul>
					<li>XML based configuration support - ability to define jobs and triggers in XML configuration file</li>
					<li>Spring.NET support - actually I've already got running code that seems to work but there are still some issues to solve</li>
				</ul>
				<p>
					After XML configuration is working and released (planned for 0.7) it's getting close to 1.0 time. Even though
					Quartz.NET is quite production ready as-is, it'll be considered 1.0 when it's also feature ready.
				</p>
				<p>
					Please remember, It's your feedback that drives this project! So don't hesitate to bring up the the good and the bad
					in Quartz.NET. We gladly accept bug reports (better yet with test code to illustrate and maybe even a patch to fix it!)
					to our <a href="http://jira.opensymphony.com/browse/QRTZNET">JIRA issue tracker</a> and welcome questions and help 
					requests to <a href="http://groups.google.com/group/quartznet">Quartz.NET mailing list</a>. It would also be great
					to hear about projects/products using Quartz.NET!
				</p>
			</section>

			<section>
				<title>Quartz.NET 0.6 Released</title>
				<p>
				<div class="descr">August 4, 2007 by Marko Lahma</div>
				</p>
				<p>
					Quartz.NET 0.6 has been released. 
				</p>
				<p>
					This both feature and bug fix release. The new biggest feature is AdoJobStore
					that currently supports SQL Server, Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL and SQLite.
					With AdoJobStore comes also clustering. Please give it a go (Example 13 has an example 
					for SQL Server) and give us feedback!
				</p>
				<p>
					This release also fixes many problems found by users, most notably CronExpression problems
					when having a more frequent firing schedule, like every nth second or minute.
				</p>
				<p>
					Now minimal configuration is also automatically loaded from Quartz.NET embedded resource, 
					so if you don't want to change the default configuration, you don't need to type anything anymore.
					See <a href="http://jira.opensymphony.com/secure/ReleaseNote.jspa?projectId=10110&amp;styleName=Html&amp;version=21710">
					release notes</a> for more details.
				</p>
				<p>
					You should be also aware of some <strong>breaking changes</strong>, please check 
					changelog.txt in the distribution root.
				</p>
				<p>
					Grab it from <a href="download.html">downloads page</a>.
				</p>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Quartz.NET 0.5 Released</title>
				<div class="descr">June 17, 2007 by Marko Lahma</div>
				<p>
					Quartz.NET 0.5 has been released. 
				</p>
				<p>
					Version 0.5 is a feature and a bug fix release. Release adds functionality
					from Java Quartz 1.6 (excluding XML and database job stores). All users
					are advised to upgrade because this release fixes problems found in cron
					scheduling and other minor problems.
				</p>
				<p>
					Grap it from <a href="download.html">downloads page</a>.
				</p>
			</section>
			
			<section>
				<title>Quartz.NET 0.4.1 Released</title>
				<div class="descr">March 24, 2007 by Marko Lahma</div>
				<p>
					Quartz.NET 0.4.1 has been released. 
				</p>
				<p>
					Version 0.4.1 is a bug fix release that addresses problems found in CronTrigger.
				</p>
				<p>
					Grap it from <a href="download.html">downloads page</a>.
				</p>
			</section>
			
			<section>
				<title>Quartz.NET Tutorial Online</title>
				<div class="descr">March 24, 2007 by Marko Lahma</div>			
				<p>
				Tutorial has been ported from Java side to serve as starting point for Quartz.NET development. There may still be some 
				rough edges to smooth an minor inaccurasies but it should be enough to get you going.
				</p>	
				<p>
				Go to <a href="tutorial.html">Tutorial section</a>.
				</p>
			</section>
			
			<section>
				<title>Quartz.NET 0.4 Released</title>
				<div class="descr">March 4, 2007 by Marko Lahma</div>
				<p>
					Quartz.NET 0.4, the initial version of Quartz.NET was released today. 
				</p>
				<p>
					Version 0.4 is the first public release with core features including:
					<ul>
						<li>SimpleTrigger and CronTrigger</li>
						<li>RAMJobStore as job store implementation</li>
					</ul>
				</p>
				<p>
					Grap it from <a href="download.html">downloads page</a>.
				</p>
			</section>
				
		</section>
	</body>
</document>